ふっん
ふっん ふっん
ふっん ふっ
Those despicable man-hunters!
卑しい人狩りどもめ
混乱に乗じ
この城に土足で足を踏み入れよって
Taking advantage of the chaos to force
their way into our homes...
ふっ　っに
っう
I have a boat prepared in the back.
この奥に船を用意してあります
Now, hurry.
さあ お急ぎを
姉上様？
Sister...
I just remembered something I must do.
少し 用事を思い出しましたわ
Katumau, take Delihourai and go on ahead.
カトゥマウ
デリホウライを連れて 先にお行きなさい
You mustn't! Allow me to...
いきません
私めが
You could hardly buy us much time.
あなたでは 時間稼ぎにもなりませんわ
ですが
But still!
Besides, I need you to take care of this child.
それより この子を頼みますわ
Sister, where are you going?
姉上様
どこへ行くの？
デリ 強くなりなさい
Deli, you be strong.
No, I don't want you to go!
やだ
行っちゃやだよ
You have to come with us!
姉上様も一緒じゃなきゃ やだよ
What are you doing!? Hurry!
何をしている
急ぎなさい
ぬうううあああ
-ぬううああ　うあ
-ん
-やだ　姉上様あ
-ん んん
No! Sister!
うふ
でええい
Become stronger than anyone.
Become a greater man than anyone.
誰よりも強く
誰よりも大きな男に
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空　果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に　充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼(はね)を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ　行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから　一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
ふん ふん はっ　ふん ふん はっ
Farewells
ふん ふん はっ
Good, they haven't detected our presence.
いいぞ
こちらの存在に気付いていない
Lord Delihourai, any carelessness
now will surely prove fatal.
デリホウライ殿
油断は死を招きます
うっ　油断などしていない
I won't be making any careless moves.
Let's go!
ゆくぞ！
うおおおおおおおああああああ
-ああ ああ
-敵襲
Enemy attack!
ぬう　でや
うふ
Wh... What are they doing here!?
な なぜこんなところに
う ふふうふ　うあ
がああう
う ふふうふ うああ
It's just a lone woman! Charge!
ええい　たかが女一人だ
かかれえ
-ぎいやあああ
-うっ
Sh... She's a monster!
ば ばけもの
-うっ
-逃がすか
Don't let them escape!
Lord Delihourai, it is too
dangerous to pursue them!
デリホウライ殿
深追いは危険です
あっ 何？
What the...
Don't get in my way!
邪魔をするな
Oh, do pardon me! My arm was a little tired.
あら ごめんなさい
ちょっと腕が疲れてしまいましたの
Lord Delihourai...
デリホウライ殿
We have sustained casualties as well.
こちらにも犠牲が出ています
We must withdraw before the enemy
sends in its main force.
敵の本陣が来る前に
All right, withdraw!
よおし
撤収する
-うああう　あああはははは　うう
-いい子　いい子　ふふ
Good girl, good girl!
We succeeded in opening up some areas,
ひとまず 解放には成功しましたが
but we need a plan of action going forward.
さて
今後の方針についてです
Of course, we'll continue this battle!
無論 今の戦いを続ける
I agree to that. The momentum
is on our side now.
某も賛成です
今 勢いは我らの側にあります
Isn't there something you've forgotten?
忘れていることがあるのではなくて？
What?
何？
Everyone is quite exhausted now.
皆さん もう随分と疲れています
Bringing those who are not soldiers into this
battle with us was not an ideal plan.
兵ではない彼らを連れて戦うことは
得策ではありません
Let us let the injured and the
women and children leave.
負傷兵と女 子どもは外へ逃がしましょう
That way we can fight on without reservations.
そうすれば 心おきなく戦えます
But...
しかし
What's that?
何だ？
What is it?
何事か？
I know a way to sneak into that castle.
私
あの城に忍び込む道を知ってましてよ
What?
何？
That castle pumps a tremendous amount of
water from an underground lake beneath it.
あの城は地下の湖から
大量の水をくみ上げています
We can sneak in the castle
using those waterways.
そこの水路からなら忍び込めますわ
Is that true!?
本当か？
But how do you know?
しかし なぜ分かる？
っふ　ケナムですもの
Well, I am a slave after all.
I've become familiar with all
the secret paths, you see.
裏道には詳しくなるものですわ
Can I trust this information?
その話 信用できるのか
It's the chieftain's duty to discern that.
それを判断なされるのが
おさの役目ですわ
We're going to strike the final
blow of this battle!
この戦いに 終止符を打つ
But there is a problem...
でも問題がありますわ
Since we're using a narrow waterway,
only a small number will be able to go.
狭い水路を通るから
少人数でしか行けないこと
Not to mention the fact that you will emerge
in the middle of enemy territory.
それに敵の真っ只中に出ることになるな
Yes...
As long as I can get inside, I don't mind
exchanging my life for their king's!
敵の懐に出られるのなら
向こうの皇(オゥルォ)と刺し違えてでも
What are you saying!?
何をおっしゃいます
Delihourai-sama, if you perish, who will
carry on the line of Karulawaturei?
デリホウライ様に死なれてしまっては
誰がカルラゥアツゥレイを
率いてゆくのですか
I don't want to let this chance go.
この期を逃したくはない
Delihourai-sama, we'll make a diversion then.
デリホウライ様
ならば 我々が囮になります
What!?
何だと？
We'll draw the enemy forces outside,
and make time for you to get in.
外で敵を引き受けます
その隙にどうか中へ
We all feel for our comrades.
仲間を思う気持ちは
同じということですわ
Lord Delihourai, you must win this war!
デリホウライ殿
この戦 何としても勝つのです
We shall win this war and
finally obtain freedom!
この戦に勝利し 我らは自由を手に入れる
The freedom that we all seek!
皆が求めている 自由を
YEAH!
うふ
-っはは っはは
-くう くう
I have a favor to ask of you.
貴様に頼みがあるのだが
What is it?
何ですか
When the fighting is over,
would you hand Karula over to me?
戦いが終わったら
カルラを譲ってくれないか
What?
Please! I'll give you anything
you desire. I beg of you.
頼む
望みの物は何でも譲ろう
このとおりだ
Well, I do not think this problem can
be settled with possessions.
いや そういうふうに
物でどうこう出来る問題ではないでしょう
Yeah, I suppose not.
あ そうだよな
But why do you make such a request?
しかし なぜそんなことを
She's the first person ever to hit me like that.
俺をあんなふうに殴ってくれたのは
あの女が初めてなんだ
And she sort of reminds me of my older sister,
who I was separated from long ago.
それに どことなく
生き別れた姉上と似ているのだ
っは まるで正反対なのにな
Although, the two are complete opposites.
Your sister?
姉上？
My sister was kind, dainty and elegant.
姉上は優しく しとやかで かれんで
She's the ideal that I yearn for.
俺の理想 憧れだ
I haven't seen a woman greater than my sister!
姉上以上の女性など
これまでに見たことがない
That is the complete opposite...
それは正反対だ
Can't sleep?
眠れないのか？
You can't either, Master?
主様も？
No...
What do you plan to do after
tomorrow's battle?
明日の戦いの後 どうするつもりだ？
I'll return to Tuskuru.
トゥスクルに戻りますわ
Are you sure about that?
良いのか
As long as one has food to sustain
oneself throughout the day,
人は その日生きていけるだけの糧と
the lullaby of the insects to
listen to at night,
虫たちのユカウラを聞きながら
大地の寝床に横たわれば
and the vast earth to lay one's head
upon, then that is enough.
それで十分
But are you comfortable throwing away
your past like that?
しかし そうやって過去を捨てて
平気なのか
What about you, Master?
主様は？
You once told me that you have no
recollections of your own past.
以前 私におっしゃいましたわね
自分には過去の記憶が無いって
Yes...
But there was someone who said that
it does not change who I am now.
だが そんな私も
私であることに変わりないと
言ってくれる人がいた
That is why I strive to live.
だから生きていける
Then it's the same for me.
ならば私も同じことですわ
I see.
そうか
Besides, I haven't been able to
throw all of it away.
それに 過去は
捨て切れるものではありませんもの
Enemy attack!
敵襲
We must hold out until Delihourai-sama returns!
デリホウライ様が戻って来るまで
何としても耐えるのだ
Lord Hakuoro...
ハクオロ殿
Hakuoro, there's something I want to ask you.
ハクオロ
聞いておきたいことがある
Is it about that again?
また その話ですか
A certain lady asked me to lend you a hand.
とある女性に
あなたに力を貸してやってくれと
頼まれまして
Katumau-sama, at this rate...
カトゥマウ様
このままでは
Delihourai-sama!
デリホウライ様
皇(オゥルォ)の間ですわ
It's the king's chambers.
This is...
こ これは
っは
It... it's awful!
ひ ひどい
It's said that human fertilizer produces
the most beautiful flowers.
人を苗床にしたものが
一番美しい花を咲かせるそうですわ
Then, this is all...
それじゃあ
これ 全部が
How do you like them?
お気に召してもらえて？
っは
It's him!
あいつが
Suonkasu...
スオンカス
It's been a while, Karula.
久しぶりですわね カル
っあ
I put my heart into growing these, just for you.
あなたのために
思いを込めて育てましたの
Do you know him?
知っているのか
Do I, indeed.
さあ どうなのでしょうね
Delihourai, concentrate on the battle at hand!
デリホウライ
今は戦いに集中しろ
Karula, you can tell me about this later!
カルラ 後で聞かせてもらうぞ
For the freedom of our comrades,
I will defeat you!
我らの同胞の自由のため
貴様を倒す
Oh my, what a spirited boy.
あら 威勢のいい坊やね
どけえ
Outta my way!
ふんっ
ぬんっ
ふんっ はっ
がう がう
ふん くっ くそ
Damn it!
He's right in front of me, and yet...
目の前だというのに
That man...
あの男
You've finally come back to me.
やっと私の所へ帰って来てくれたわ
Sorry to disappoint you, but I have
no intentions of coming back.
残念ですけど
帰って来たつもりはありませんわよ
うっふっふ
You've come back.
あなたは帰って来たのよ
What are you saying!?
何を言ってる？
You silly boy...
お馬鹿さん
I've never had any interest
in this slave rebellion.
ケナムの反乱など
初めから興味は無くてよ
I've had only one objective.
私の目的は一つ
To lay this bed of flowers in
order for her to find me.
あなたに見つけてもらうために
この花畑を作ること
っあ
Karula! No, Karulawaturei!
カル
いえ カルラゥアツゥレイ
You've finally come back to me!
やっと帰って来てくれたのですね
Karulawaturei!?
カルラゥアツゥレイ？
This rebellion...
この反乱
It was nothing but a ploy to draw me out,
right from the very start.
最初から私を誘い出すために
仕組まれていたということですのね
Brilliant deduction, Karulawaturei.
You are indeed clever.
さすが カルラゥアツゥレイ
賢いわ
I did all this to make you happy.
あなたに喜んでもらうために
趣向を凝らしてみたのよ
どうかしら？
How is it? Your beloved country and
these larumanionu blossoms!
あなたの好きだったふるさと
ラルマニオヌのお花よ
What!?
何だと？
Just for something like this...
そんなことで
He's insane.
狂っている
あなたが私の所へ戻って来てくれれば
If you'd just come back to me, you'll live like
you did when you were the empress.
皇女の時と同じ
いえ もっとぜいたくな
暮らしをさせてあげるわ
No, an even more luxurious life!
Empress?
皇女？
Imperial life is not only stifling,
but very boring as well.
王宮での生活など
窮屈な上に退屈なだけですわ
Then you truly are...
やはり
あなたは
っん
Then, I'll have to leave you with
no choice but to come back.
ならば
あなたが私の元に
来ざるをえないようにしてあげる
Stay by me!
私から離れるな
Yes!
はい
ふん てや てや
ん　っん　はっ
ん ん どけえ
Move it!
いや てや　ふん　行け
おう
Damn you!
貴様だけは
っんっふふ
You really are a simpleton.
本当にあなたは単細胞
Is charging forward all you know how to do?
突進してくることしか出来ないのかしら
Delihourai, stand up!
デリホウライ  立ちなさい
You don't have to tell me to!
言われるまでも
It's just like before.
あの時と同じね
Deli, you're so useless.
デリ あなたは駄目な子
っは
He's wrong.
違う
You stood up for everyone.
-あなたは皆のために立ちあがりましたわ
-あっ
うふふ　そしてあなたも以前と同じ
And you're the same as before too.
ああ カルラ
Oh, Karula!
あなたが再び私の元にやって来るこの瞬間を
どれほど楽しみにしてきたことか
How I've anticipated this moment!
To see you come back to me again!
でえやああ
っは
Delihourai!
デリホウライ
Yes!
はい
ぬううああ
っああ
This is for all of my comrades suffering!
今までの我が同胞の苦しみ
-ふん
-あっ
Karulawaturei!
カルラゥアツゥレイ
っん
Don't you sully that name!
その名を汚すな
You are my sister, aren't you?
姉上様なのですね
Sister, how I have longed to see you again.
姉上様
どれだけ
再びあなたにお会いしたかったか
You must have me confused
with someone else.
私を誰かと間違えているようですけど
You've got the wrong person.
人違いですわ
What... what are you saying!?
何を
何を言ってるんですか
Now be quiet!
黙りなさい
っあ
今 この時も 外では
多くの同胞が戦っていますわ
At this very moment, many of your
comrades are fighting outside.
Isn't there something you still
need to do for them?
その同胞のために あなたにはまだ
やることがあるのではなくて？
Go now.
お行きなさい
We can talk after that.
お話なら その後でも出来ますわ
I understand.
分かりました
So please, promise me!
That you won't go away again.
だから約束してください
もうどこにも行かないって
Sure!
Well, now, shall we head back then?
さあてと
帰りましょうか
Huh? But you said you'd wait.
でも待ってるって
Did I say such a thing?
そんなこと言いましたかしら？
But you promised...
そんな
約束って
Eruruu-sama...
エルルゥ様
But... but that's so depressing!
でも
でもそんなの悲し過ぎます
Karula-san, you're a fool! You're a big fool!
カルラさんは馬鹿です
大馬鹿です
I guess so.
そうですわね
I think that too sometimes.
時々 自分でもそう思う時がありますわ
But that's so...
そんなのって
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
Thank you.
ありがと
っは
Is it okay now?
もう いいのか
Yes, I'm fine now.
ええ もう大丈夫ですわ
I am Delihourai of the Girinagiya,
ギリヤギナのデリホウライ
and I have defeated our
arch-nemesis, Suonkasu!
怨敵 スオンカスを討ち取ったり
I hereby declare the independence
of Karulawaturei!
今ここに
カルラゥアツゥレイの自立を宣言する
ふん
おいっと
Weird...
変
Ever since we came back,
he hasn't left Yuzu-cchi's side.
帰って来てからというもの
ユズっちのそばを離れなくなっちゃった
カミュちゃん
Camus-chan?
Oh, then let's all go together!
あ じゃあ 皆で行こう
Wait up, you guys!
待てよ お前ら
I'm coming too!
俺も行くぞ
Big brother, are you even coming
to the baths with us?
お兄様
お風呂にも付いて来られるの？
It's been a while since I've
taken a bath with you.
久しぶり
お兄様と一緒のお風呂
No, that's not what I was planning to do!
あ いや 違う　そんなつもりじゃ
He's late! How long is he going
to keep us waiting?
遅い
いつまで待たせるつもりだ
Delihourai-sama, we've come to thank him.
Don't be like that!
デリホウライ様
お礼に参ったというのに
そのようなことを
As a king myself, I must always be on
equal footing with other kings.
皇(オゥルォ)を名乗るからには
常に他の皇(オゥルォ)とは
対等の立場でなければならん
If my standing should be diminished, then
I'll no longer be recognized as a king.
それが崩れる時
俺は皇(オゥルォ)ではなくなる
Isn't that right?
違うか？
んん それは
But my lord...
相変わらず威勢がいいな
I see you are spirited as ever.
貴様が
You're the king of Tuskuru!?
トゥスクルの皇(オゥルォ)？
Now then, this is supposedly
our very first meeting.
さて
貴公とは初対面のはずだが
It is a pleasure to meet you.
My name is Delihourai.
初にお目に掛かる
俺の名はデリホウライ
I have come to thank you for the aid
and supplies you provided us.
物資支援の件
礼を言わせていただくために来た
I do not need your thanks.
礼はいらん
What did you say?
何だと
I had originally planned to forsake you.
私はお前たちを見捨てるつもりでいた
However, a certain woman
asked me to help you.
だが ある女に
お前たちを助けてくれと頼まれたのだ
っは
And that person that asked you,
is she doing well?
その者は元気であるか
Yes, too well in fact.
元気過ぎて
So much so, that she's quite a
handful for me to deal with.
困るほどにね
っはは
Delihourai-sama, is something the matter?
デリホウライ様
どうかされましたか？
No...
いや
It's nothing.
何でもない
If you go now, you can still make it in time.
今行けばまだ間に合う
It's okay to go with him.
一緒に行ってもいいんだぞ
Even more so, since he is your only kin.
ただ一人の肉親なら なおのこと
Master, you are mistaken.
主様は勘違いしていますわ
The person you see before you
ここにいるのは
is a mere woman by the name of
Karula, who serves you.
主様に仕える カルラという名の一人の女
Farewell...
さよなら
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
孤独の中求む
魂から結びつき　私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼　祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼　弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす　輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし　詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
First Battle